<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>https://blog.fetinin.dev/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://blog.fetinin.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t embed pointers</title>
      <link>https://blog.fetinin.dev/posts/dont-embed-pointers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fetinin.dev/posts/dont-embed-pointers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Go, it&amp;rsquo;s important to be aware of potential bugs when embedding pointers within structs. This article explores such a scenario and provides alternative solutions to avoid confusion and errors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go has new generic slices and map packages</title>
      <link>https://blog.fetinin.dev/posts/go-has-new-generic-slices-and-map-packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fetinin.dev/posts/go-has-new-generic-slices-and-map-packages/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since the introduction of generics in Go 1.18, there have been discussions about adding new helper functions to the standard library to cover most frequent operations. After more than a year, two new libraries with generics will be added&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; into the Go standard library starting from Go 1.21.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubectl cheatsheet</title>
      <link>https://blog.fetinin.dev/posts/kubectl-cheatsheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fetinin.dev/posts/kubectl-cheatsheet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Throughout the years of using kubernetes as a developer I&amp;rsquo;ve collected a bunch of useful commands that helped me to debug issues and have better understanding of what is happening in the cluster.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Safe git force push</title>
      <link>https://blog.fetinin.dev/posts/safe-git-force-push/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fetinin.dev/posts/safe-git-force-push/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ve likely been in this situation before. You make some minor code fixes, do &lt;code&gt;git commit --amend&lt;/code&gt; to add them to the current commit, and do &lt;code&gt;git push --force&lt;/code&gt;. Then, you happily open pull request and see that you&amp;rsquo;ve deleted you&amp;rsquo;re colleagues commit.😩&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Gonkey -- Testing automation tool</title>
      <link>https://blog.fetinin.dev/posts/gonkey/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fetinin.dev/posts/gonkey/introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/lamoda/gonkey&#34;&gt;Gonkey&lt;/a&gt; is a testing automation tool that can test your service API without a single line of code.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fundamentals of software architecture book overview. Part 1. Who is an Architect?</title>
      <link>https://blog.fetinin.dev/posts/fundamentals-of-software-architecture-overview/part-1.-who-is-an-architect/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fetinin.dev/posts/fundamentals-of-software-architecture-overview/part-1.-who-is-an-architect/</guid>
      <description>Fundamentals of software architecture is a book by Mark Richards and Neal Ford — hands-on practitioners who have taught software architecture classes professionally for years—focus on architecture principles that apply across all technology stacks.
This book left me with good basis of what role software architect plays in a company and extended my knowledge of different architecture patterns. In the following series of articles I&amp;rsquo;ll write about topics from this book that I liked most.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://blog.fetinin.dev/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fetinin.dev/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Denis 💁🏻‍♂️💻 Golang and Python developer who secretly loves frontend, but most of the time works as a backend developer at UCB.
I have experience with microservices and event-driven architecture. I&amp;rsquo;ve worked in e-commerce on app and website backends, as well as over 20 microservices that provide discounts and coupons, catalog navigation, checkout, cart, and other features for our customers.
I enjoy working in small to medium teams and helping to understand business requirements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://blog.fetinin.dev/speaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fetinin.dev/speaking/</guid>
      <description>All content on this page is in Russian because all my public speaking is in Russian, so it doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense to write an English description.
CDC на коленке Оффлайн выступление на митапе Dev Day от 2GIS.
Внезапно возникшее желание разобраться в том как можно работать из Go переросло в доклад, где вымышленному Серёге в канун нового года нужно придумать как переехать с Posgtres на новую хайповую базу без даунтайма. Справится ли Серёга?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debug info</title>
      <link>https://blog.fetinin.dev/debug/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fetinin.dev/debug/</guid>
      <description>Last update time: 2023-08-06 13:43:05 +0300 MSK</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
